rollercoastertycoon.com 2007-12-13

# Atari - US - Privacy

|  |  |   
---|---|---  
| 

|  |  |  |   
---|---|---  
|    
**ATARI ONLINE PRIVACY STATEMENT**

ATARI KIDS PRIVACY POLICY

Last updated October 6, 2006

Welcome to Atari!

**OUR PRIVACY COMMITMENT**

[](http://www.esrb.org/confirm/atari-confirmation.jsp) Atari, Inc., and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, "Atari") respect the privacy rights of our online visitors and recognizes the importance of protecting all information that you may choose to share with us. To further this commitment, we have adopted this Online Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") to guide how we collect, store, and use the information you provide us.

This Privacy Statement and the certification seal shown on this page confirms that Atari is a member in good standing of [ESRB's Privacy Online Program](http://www.esrb.org/). ESRB's Privacy Online Program is designed to ensure that our website's information disclosure practices are responsible and appropriate. To protect your privacy, we have voluntarily undertaken this privacy initiative and all of our websites have been reviewed and certified by ESRB Privacy Online to meet established online information collection and use practices. As part of this privacy program, we are subject to frequent audits of our websites and other enforcement and accountability mechanisms administered independently by the ESRB.

**TABLE OF CONTENTS

Q1. What information does this Privacy Statement cover?  
Q2. What types of personally identifiable information do we collect about our guests?  
Q3. How is your personally identifiable information used and shared?  
Q4. What choices do you have about the collection, use, and sharing of your personally identifiable information?  
Q5. What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard your personally identifiable information?  
Q6. How can you update your personal information and profile?  
Q7. How can you ask questions, or send us comments, about this Privacy Policy?  
Q8. How will you know if we amend this Privacy Policy?

**

|  **Q1.**|  **What information does this Privacy Statement cover?**  
---|---  
**A1.**|  This Privacy Policy applies only to personal information collected on the websites where this Privacy Policy is posted, and does not apply to any other information collected by Atari through any other means.

This Privacy Policy applies to use and sharing of personal information collected on and after the date that this Privacy Policy is posted.

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information submitted and collected online, and does not apply to information that may be collected by Atari offline. This Privacy Policy applies only to websites maintained by Atari, and not to our international affiliates (Atari in France, United Kingdom, Italy, etc.), or any websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we link. Atari is therefore not responsible for the content or activities provided on those websites.

Finally, the terms of this Privacy Policy are subject to all applicable laws.   
  
back to top  
**Q2.**|  **What types of personally identifiable information do we collect about our guests?**  
---|---  
**A2.**|  We don't require personal information to access our website. However, if you prefer not to disclose personal information, you will not be able to enjoy certain features of our website. Personal information is information that identifies you and may be used to contact you. To offer our guests certain features on our website, we collect several types of personal information.

**Children**

We don't knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. We take steps to ensure that those who wish to register personal information on our websites meet certain age requirements before they can do so. We take kids privacy seriously, and encourage parents to play an active role in their children's online experience at all times. 

**Information You Provide to Us**

All of the personal information we receive comes directly from our guests. We collect personal information from our guests to:

1\. register for our website  
2\. register our products  
3\. subscribe to our newsletter  
4\. register for community forum  
5\. participate in polls, surveys, and questionnaires  
6\. use e-cards, wish lists, and tell-a-friend features  
7\. purchase a product at one of our online stores  
8\. participate in contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions  
9\. receive technical support

Typically, this information includes:

1\. name  
2\. email address  
3\. telephone number  
4\. shipping and billing address, and  
5\. for those purchasing products online, credit card information.

Additionally, we may also collect other types of non-personal information (known as demographic information) such as your age or date of birth, gender, hobbies, platform preferences, and other game ownership and preferences. This demographic information may be associated with your personal information.

**Information Collected Through Technology**

We collect information through technology to make our websites more interesting and useful to you. For example, when you come to one of our websites, we collect your IP address. An IP address is often associated with the portal through which you enter the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. Standing alone, your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use IP addresses to collect information regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our websites. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information.

**Cookies**

Our websites also use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a Website sends to your computer while you are viewing the Website. We and other companies use cookies for a variety of purposes. For example, when you return to one of our websites after logging in, cookies provide information to the website so that the website will remember who you are. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You can do this through your browser (like Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your web experience smoother, like the features mentioned above, and some of our services may not function properly.

**Web Beacons**

Our websites use a variety of technical methods for tracking purposes, including Web beacons. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of websites. We also use these technical methods to analyze the traffic patterns on our websites, such as the frequency with which our users visit various parts of our websites. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf. We also use these technical methods in HTML e-mails that we send our guests to determine whether our guests have opened those e-mails or clicked on links in those e-mails. The information from use of these technical methods may be collected in a form that is personally identifiable.

**Network Advertisers**

Many advertisements are managed and placed on our websites by third parties. These companies are called "network advertisers". Network advertisers who place advertisements on our websites may also use cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information when you click on or move your cursor over one of their banner advertisements. You may not realize this information is being collected. In some cases, we may have access to information from web beacons and cookies used by network advertisers on our sites and this information may permit us to identify other sites that you have visited that are also associated with the network advertiser.

Finally, once you've clicked on an advertisement and have left our Websites, our Privacy Policy no longer applies and you must read the privacy policy of the advertiser to see how your personal information will be handled on their website.   
  
back to top  
**Q3.**|  **How is your personally identifiable information used and shared?**  
---|---  
**A3.**|  We don't share, sell, or rent your personal information to third parties without your consent. We don't require personal information to access our website. However, if you prefer not to disclose personal information, you will not be able to enjoy certain features of our website.

Whatever the purpose may be, we will only collect information to the extent reasonably necessary to fulfill your requests and our legitimate business objectives.

**Atari Tools and Updates**

Information collected from those who voluntarily submit it to us is used to provide services like updates on special events, game news, and email announcements of interest to our users. Occasionally, we share your personal information (e.g., email address) with a third party sponsor, co-sponsor, or other reputable third party that provides products or services that may be of interest to you. Moreover, if you register for access to our blogs or message boards, we will use your personal information to enable you to view and post messages on the boards. However, you should understand that community forums, blogs, and message boards are tools that allow you to communicate with members of the online community. As such, whenever you give out personal information in public areas, that information can be collected and used by people you don't know.

**Operational Uses**

We may also use your personal information for other purposes such as "Operational Uses". For example, we may use your information to send you administrative communications either about your account with us or about features of our websites, including any future changes to this Privacy Policy.

We occasionally use other companies, agents or contractors to perform services necessary to our operations. For example, we have partnered with other companies to personalize our web pages, process credit card transactions, analyze customers. interaction with our website, and process consumer surveys. We also provide postal addresses to the U.S. Post Office for delivery purposes. In the course of providing such services, these companies may have contact with your personally identifying information. These entities have agreed to securely store and maintain the personal information received from us.

**Aggregate Information**

Finally, we may take your personally identifiable information and make it non-personally identifiable, either by combining it with information about other individuals (aggregating your information with information about other individuals), or by removing characteristics (such as your name) that make the information personally identifiable to you (de-personalizing your information). Given the nature of this information, no restrictions apply under this Privacy Policy on our right to aggregate or de-personalize your personal information, and we may use and share in any way with third parties the resulting non-personally identifiable information.

**Business Information**

For practical reasons, we treat personal information submitted to us in a business capacity different from information we receive in a non-business capacity. Personal information submitted to us in a business capacity (e.g. resumes, event sponsorship, etc.) may be shared with third parties, depending on the nature of the inquiry.

**Purchase or Sale of Businesses**

From time to time, we may purchase a business or sell one or more of our businesses and your personally identifiable information may be transferred as a part of the purchase or sale. If we purchase a business, the personally identifiable information received with that business would be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy, if it is practicable and permissible to do so. If we sell a business, we will include provisions in the selling contract requiring the purchaser to treat your personally identifiable information in the same manner required by this Privacy Policy (including any amendments to this Privacy Policy). The provisions of this paragraph will also apply if we are sold as part of bankruptcy proceedings.

**Disclosures Required By Law and Disclosures to Help Protect the Security and Safety of Our Websites and Others**

We will disclose personal information when we believe in good faith that such disclosures (a) are required by law, including, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena, or (b) will help to: enforce our Terms of Use; enforce contest, sweepstakes, promotions, and/or game rules; protect your safety or security, including the safety and security of property that belongs to you; and/or, protect the safety and security of our websites or third parties.   
  
back to top  
**Q4.**|  **What choices do you have about the collection, use, and sharing of your personally identifiable information?**  
---|---  
**A4.**|  As mentioned above, you have control over the personal information you submit to us. If at any time you decide to remove your personal information from our database, you may do so by emailing us at [webmaster@atari.com](mailto:webmaster@atari.com), or contacting us via the Atari mailing address.   
back to top  
**Q5.**|  **What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard your personally identifiable information?**  
---|---  
**A5.**|  The security and confidentiality of your information is extremely important to us. We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect your personal information from unauthorized access and improper use. From time to time, we review our security procedures to consider appropriate new technology and methods. However, please understand that, despite our best efforts, no security measure is perfect or impenetrable.   
back to top  
**Q6.**|  **How can you update your personal information and profile?**  
---|---  
**A6.**|  You can access and update the contact information you gave us during registration (that is, your e-mail address or any other information that would directly enable us to contact you), by emailing us at [webmaster@atari.com](mailto:webmaster@atari.com)  
back to top  
  
**Q7.**|  **How can you ask questions, or send us comments, about this Privacy Policy?**  
---|---  
**A7.**|  If you have questions or wish to send us comments about this Privacy Policy, please send us an e-mail us with your questions or comments to call or write us at:

Atari, Inc.  
Attn.: Webmaster  
417 Fifth Avenue  
New York, NY 10016  
(212) 726-6500  
webmaster@atari.com

Please be assured that any personal information that you provide in communications to the above email and postal mail addresses will not be used to send you promotional materials, unless you request it.

Atari is a licensee of the ESRB's Privacy Online Program. If you believe that we have not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact ESRB at <http://www.esrb.org/privacy/contact.jsp>

ESRB  
Attn.: Privacy Online Program  
317 Madison Avenue, 22nd Floor  
New York, NY 10017  
212-759-0700  
  
back to top  
**Q8.**|  **How will you know if we amend this Privacy Policy?**  
---|---  
**A8.**|  We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, or share your personal information, we will notify you by sending you an email at the last email address that you provided us, or by prominently posting notice of the changes on the websites covered by this Privacy Policy. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective 30 days following our dispatch of an email notice to you or 30 days following our posting of notice of the changes on the Websites covered by this Privacy Policy.

Please note that, at all times, you are responsible for updating your personal information to provide us your current email address. If the last email address that you have provided us is not valid, or for any other reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the email containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the changes described in the notice.   
  
back to top  
  
* * *

**ATARI KIDS PRIVACY POLICY**

ATARI ONLINE PRIVACY STATEMENT

Last updated December 12, 2006

Welcome to Atari!

**OUR PRIVACY COMMITMENT**

[](http://www.esrb.org/confirm/atari-confirmation.jsp) Atari has developed its websites with the goal of creating an enjoyable experience for all users. This Kids Privacy Policy is designed to answer your questions regarding our privacy policies and principles with respect to children under the age of 13. 

Building on our general Privacy Policy, we recognize the need to provide additional privacy protections when children visit the sites on which this Kids' Privacy Policy is posted. We explain those additional protections in this Kids' Privacy Policy. 

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA") requires that we inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from children under 13 years of age; and that we obtain the consent of parents and guardians in order for children under 13 years of age to use certain features of our Web sites. Below we explain how we do that for these "kids." Also, when we use the term "parent" below, we mean to include legal guardians. 

This certification seal shown on this page confirms that Atari is a member in good standing of [ESRB's Privacy Online Program](http://www.esrb.org/privacy/index.jsp). ESRB's Privacy Online Program is designed to ensure that our website’s information disclosure practices are responsible and appropriate. To protect your privacy, we have voluntarily undertaken this privacy initiative and all of our websites have been reviewed and certified by ESRB Privacy Online to meet established online information collection and use practices. As part of this privacy program, ESRB independently audits our websites, and administers other enforcement and accountability mechanisms.

 **TABLE OF CONTENTS

Q1. What types of information do we collect about kids?  
Q2. How do we use and share the personally identifiable information that we collect from kids?  
Q3. How do we notify and obtain consent from parents for the collection of personal information from their kids?  
Q4. How can parents access, change or delete personally identifiable information about their kids?  
Q5. What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard kids’ personally identifiable information?  
Q6. How will we notify parents if our Kids’ Privacy Policy changes?  
Q7. Who do guests contact with questions or concerns about our Kids’ Privacy Policy?

**

 **Q1.**|  **What types of information do we collect about kids?**  
---|---  
**A1.**|  Kids can surf Atari’s sites, view content, and enjoy many features without any personal information being collected. We don’t collect personal information from kids while they use our sites unless they register on Atari’s sites. 

We collect personal information directly from kids to: 

  1. register on Atari’s websites 
  2. participate in games, reward programs, contests, sweepstakes, events, or other promotions 
  3. participate in polls, surveys, or questionnaires 
  4. create a wishlist or purchase at one of our online stores 
  5. send questions or receive technical support 

Typically, this information includes: 
  1. name 
  2. email address 
  3. telephone number 
  4. shipping and billing address, and 
  5. for those purchasing products online, credit card information. 

We may collect demographic information (date of birth, gender, and preferences) and combine it with the child’s personal information. Atari will only collect this information if it is voluntarily and properly submitted to us by either the child or parent. The child must provide us with his or her parents’ e-mail address. Atari will then send the parent a form that must be signed and returned to Atari. 

All commercial sites directed to children under 13 are prohibited by U.S. law from conditioning a kid’s participation in an online activity on the kid's providing more personal information than is reasonably necessary. 

Some areas of our website offer features like electronic postcards that allow kids to submit personal information (e.g., email address) without first disclosing their age or obtaining verifiable parental consent. These areas of our website provide services in a way that doesn’t require prior verifiable parental consent. 

Finally, we may collect demographic information about a kid. For example, if a kid participates in a survey, we may collect those responses. Among them, we may collect age, gender, hobbies, and interests or other demographic information about gaming and preferences. We also use some passive technologies, including cookies and web beacons, to monitor traffic on our websites. This demographic information may be associated with a child’s personal information.   
  
back to top  
**Q2.**|  **How do we use and share the personally identifiable information that we collect from kids?**  
---|---  
**A2.**|  We may collect personal information from parents to allow kids to participate in certain activities offered on our websites and within our kids' subscription products. These activities may include participating in games, reward programs, contests, sweepstakes, events or other promotions; purchasing in one of our on line stores or creating a wishlist. 

Information collected from kids who voluntarily and properly submit it to us is used to provide services like newsletter subscription, updates on special events, game news, and e-mail announcements of interest to our users. Moreover, if you register for access to our blogs or message boards, we will use your personal information to enable you to view and post messages on the boards. You should understand, however, that community forums, blogs, and message boards are tools that allow you to communicate with members of the online community. So whenever you give out personal information in public areas, that information can be collected and used by people you don’t know. 

We may also use your child’s information to allow your child to send questions or request customer support. We may use your child’s information to participate in polls, surveys or questionnaires. We may also use that information to send your child email and messages with promotional information about new products and features, special offers, and other interesting events concerning new products, events and other information about Atari. 

If a parent allows us to collect personal information about their child, we may link certain information collected through technology (see the "Information Collected Through Technology" section of A2 of our General Privacy Policy) to that personal information. 

We may use the information that we collect from and about kids for our business purposes, including record-keeping, transaction fulfillment, and marketing. The contact information gathered from a kid is used to obtain consent to our information collection from their parents. 

After registration, contact information may also be used to notify users of promotional activities such as contests, sweepstakes, newsletters or new products, or functional changes to our website or privacy policy. Finally, we may use personal and demographic information for our internal marketing and study ways to better improve our services. 

If a kid wins a sweepstakes, contest or other promotional event if we have not already collected the parent’s consent, we notify the parent at the email address provided to us during the registration process, and request that the parent provide his or her postal address for purposes of delivering the prize. We may publish a winner’s first name, city, and state of residence on our web site. 

Atari may share kids’ personal information with outside entities hired to assist with internal website support operations (e.g., online product fulfillment, email services, or technical support). These entities have agreed to maintain confidentiality, security, and integrity of all the personal information they obtain from us. 

We do not share any information about a child with any third parties unless the disclosure is reasonably necessary to: 

  * comply with law, including, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena; 
  * enforce our Terms of Service, or site or game/promotion rules; 
  * in connection with the purchase or sale of assets, a merger, reorganization, bankruptcy or similar corporate transaction; or 
  * protect the safety and security of our guests and our Web sites. 

back to top  
**Q3.**|  **How do we notify and obtain consent from parents for the collection of personal information from their kids?**  
---|---  
**A3.**|  When a child under the age of 13 attempts to register with our website, we send their parent an e-mail notifying them that their child would like to register, and asking them to complete and sign a parental consent form and return it to Atari. If the parent ignores or refuses to register their child, we will delete all contact information from our database. If the parent permits the registration, their child will be granted access to the features described in the notification e-mail. 

Under federal law, parents have the option of allowing us to collect personal information from kids without consenting to the disclosure of that information to third parties.   
  
back to top  
**Q4.**|  **How can parents access, change or delete personally identifiable information about their kids?**  
---|---  
**A4.**|  At any time, a parent can access, change, or delete the personal information that we have collected from his or her kid through their Atari login and password account or by contacting our customer service department through an e-mail to [privacy@atari.com](mailto:privacy@atari.com). Please include the kid member’s name and the parent's e-mail address in the e-mail so that we can better assist you with your inquiry or request.   
back to top  
**Q5.**|  **What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard kids’ personally identifiable information?**  
---|---  
**A5.**|  We take the security and confidentiality of kids’ information very seriously. We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect kids’ personal information from unauthorized access and improper use. We regularly review our security procedures to consider appropriate new technology and methods. But please understand that, despite our best efforts, no security measure is perfect or impenetrable.   
back to top  
**Q6.**|  **How will we notify parents if our Kids’ Privacy Policy changes?**  
---|---  
**A6.**|  We may amend our Kids’ Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material changes in how we collect, use, or share your personal information, we will notify parents by sending an e-mail to the last e-mail address provided to us, or by prominently posting notice of the changes on the websites covered by this Privacy Policy. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective 30 days following our dispatch of an e-mail notice to you or 30 days following our posting of notice of the changes on the Websites covered by this Privacy Policy. We will apply material changes in our Kids' Privacy Policy only in conformance with applicable law, including any applicable provisions of COPPA that require parental consent. 

At all times, you are responsible for updating us on your current e-mail address or other contact information. If the last e-mail address you provided to us is invalid, or otherwise incapable of delivering our notice described above, our dispatch of that e-mail will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the material changes to our privacy policy.   
  
back to top  
**Q7.**|  **Who do guests contact with questions or concerns about our Kids’ Privacy Policy?**  
---|---  
**A7.**|  If you have questions or wish to send us comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us with questions or comments at: 

**Atari, Inc.**  
Attn.: Privacy Administrator  
417 Fifth Avenue  
New York, NY 10016  
212.726.6500  

Atari is a licensee of the ESRB’s Privacy Online Program. If you believe that we have not properly responded to your inquiry, please contact ESRB at http://www.esrb.org/privacy/contact.jsp 

**ESRB**  
Attn.: Privacy Online Program  
317 Madison Avenue, 22nd Floor  
New York, NY 10017  
212-759-0700  
  
back to top  
  
|  |   
  
|  |
